Guide to the Alain C. Enthoven Papers SC1295
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alain C. Enthoven Papers
1966-1968
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Enthoven, Alain C., 1930-
SC1295
1.5 Linear Feet (1 carton)
Biographical / Historical
Alain C. Einthoven is the the Marriner S. Eccles Professor of Public and Private Management, Emeritus and Senior Fellow Emeritus (by courtesy), Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies at Stanford.
Einthoven earned a BA from Stanford University in 1952; an MPhil from Oxford University in 1954; and a PhD, from Massachusetts Institute of Technology in 1956. He was a RAND Corporation economist between 1956 and 1960; a Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense from 1961 to 1965; and the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Systems Analysis from 1965 to 1969. Einthoven joined the Stanford faculty in 1973.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of Enthoven's papers from the 1960s, during which time he served as Assistant Secretary of Defense for Systems Analysis, with the Department of Defense. Papers include summaries of daily activities, meeting notes, travel files, and other materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Alain C. Enthoven, 2016.
Enthoven, Alain C., 1930-; United States. Department of Defense
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2016-129
  - untitled, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Summary of daily actions, 1967 Sep-Dec (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Summary of daily actions, 1967 Jan-Apr (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - untitled, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Admin: Summary of action items, 1966 Jun-Sep (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - OASD(SA) ImmedOffice: Daily Actions, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - untitled, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - untitled, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - untitled, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stanford University Travel, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Computer Science Advisory Committee Meeting, 1968 Oct 6-8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Summary of daily actions, 1967 May- Aug (Box 1, Folder 12)